barchart.com 2016-10-19

# Barchart.com - Privacy Policy

| 

## Terms of Use

Welcome to Barchart.com. These Terms of Use govern your use of the Barchart Network (the websites of Barchart.com, InsideStocks.com, CommodityCharts.com and InsideFutures.com, hereafter referred to as "Barchart.com"), all content, software and services (the "Services") offered through Barchart.com.

YOUR AFFIRMATIVE ACT OF USING BARCHART.COM SIGNIFIES THAT YOU AGREE TO THE FOLLOWING TERMS OF USE, AND YOU CONSENT TO THE COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION AS DISCLOSED IN THE PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE, DO NOT USE BARCHART.COM.

  1. **CHANGES TO THE TERMS OF USE.**

We may change these Terms of Use at any time. You can review the most current version of these terms by clicking on the "Terms of Use" link located at the bottom of our web pages. You are responsible for checking these terms periodically for changes. If you continue to use Barchart.com after we post changes to these Terms of Use, you are signifying your acceptance of the new terms. 

  2. **CHANGES TO BARCHART.COM  
**  
We may discontinue or change any service or feature on Barchart.com at any time and without notice.
  3. **OWNERSHIP OF INFORMATION; LICENSE TO USE BARCHART.COM; REDISTRIBUTION OF DATA**. 

Unless otherwise noted, all right, title and interest in and to Barchart.com, and all information made available through Barchart.com or its Services, in all languages, formats and media throughout the world, including all copyrights and trademarks therein, are the exclusive property of Barchart.com, its affiliates or its Data Providers. 

You may use Barchart.com and the Content offered on Barchart.com only for personal, non-commercial purposes. You may use Content offered for downloading, such as daily data files, for personal use only and subject to the rules that accompany that particular Content. You may not use any data mining, robots, or similar data gathering and extraction tools on the Content, frame any portion of Barchart.com or Content, or reproduce, reprint, copy, store, publicly display, broadcast, transmit, modify, translate, port, publish, sublicense, assign, transfer, sell, loan, or otherwise distribute the Content without our prior written consent. You may not circumvent any mechanisms included in the Content for preventing the unauthorized reproduction or distribution of the Content. For information on white-labeling Barchart content, please visit [Barchart Market Data Solutions](http://bcs.barchart.com/home.php).

EXCEPT AS OTHERWISE EXPRESSLY PERMITTED BY THE PRECEDING PARAGRAPH, YOU AGREE NOT TO REPRODUCE, RETRANSMIT, DISSEMINATE, SELL, DISTRIBUTE, PUBLISH, BROADCAST OR CIRCULATE ANY OF THE SERVICES OR MATERIALS IN ANY MANNER OR FOR ANY PURPOSES (WHETHER PERSONAL OR BUSINESS) WITHOUT THE PRIOR EXPRESS WRITTEN CONSENT OF BARCHART.COM AND/OR THE DATA PROVIDERS. IN ADDITION, YOU SHALL NOT, WITHOUT THE PRIOR EXPRESS WRITTEN CONSENT OF BARCHART.COM AND THE RELEVANT DATA PROVIDERS, MAKE COPIES OF ANY OF THE SOFTWARE OR DOCUMENTATION THAT MAY BE PROVIDED, ELECTRONICALLY OR OTHERWISE, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, TRANSLATING, DECOMPILING, DISASSEMBLING OR CREATING DERIVATIVE WORKS. 

  4. **THIRD PARTY SITES and ADVERTISERS**

Barchart.com may include links to third party websites. Some of these sites may contain materials that are objectionable, unlawful, or inaccurate. You agree that Barchart.com shall not be held liable for any trading activities or other activities that occur on any website you access through links on Barchart.com. We provide these links as a convenience, and do not endorse the content or services offered by these other sites. Any dealings that you have with advertisers found on Barchart.com are between you and the advertiser and you acknowledge and agree that we are not liable for any loss or claim you may have against an advertiser. 

  5. **DISCLAIMER REGARDING CONTENT  
**  
Barchart.com cannot and does not represent or guarantee that any of the information available through the Services or on Barchart.com is accurate, reliable, current, complete or appropriate for your needs. Various information available through the Services or on Barchart.com may be specially obtained by Barchart.com from professional businesses or organizations, such as exchanges, news providers, market data providers and other content providers (e.g., the New York Stock Exchange, NASDAQ, New York Mercantile Exchange and Dow Jones), who are believed to be sources of reliable information (collectively, the “Data Providers”).  Nevertheless, due to various factors — including the inherent possibility of human and mechanical error — the accuracy, completeness, timeliness, results obtained from use, and correct sequencing of information available through the Services and Website are not and cannot be guaranteed by Barchart.com.
  6. **DISCLAIMER REGARDING INVESTMENT DECISIONS AND TRADING**

Decisions to buy, sell, hold or trade in securities, commodities and other investments involve risk and are best made based on the advice of qualified financial professionals. Any trading in securities or other investments involves a risk of substantial losses. The practice of “Day Trading” involves particularly high risks and can cause you to lose substantial sums of money. Before undertaking any trading program, you should consult a qualified financial professional. Please consider carefully whether such trading is suitable for you in light of your financial condition and ability to bear financial risks.  Under no circumstances shall we be liable for any loss or damage you or anyone else incurs as a result of any trading or investment activity that you or anyone else engages in based on any information or material you receive through Barchart.com or our Services.

  7. **DISCLAIMER REGARDING HYPOTHETICAL PERFORMANCE RESULTS**

Hypothetical performance results have many inherent limitations, some of which are mentioned below. No representation is being made that any account will or is likely to achieve profits or losses similar to those shown. In fact, there are frequently sharp differences between hypothetical performance results and actual results subsequently achieved by any particular trading program.

One of the limitations of hypothetical performance results is that they are generally prepared with the benefit of hindsight. In addition, hypothetical trading does not involve financial risk and no hypothetical trading record can completely account for the impact of financial risk in actual trading. For example the ability to withstand losses or to adhere to a particular trading program in spite of the trading losses are material points, which can also adversely affect trading results. There are numerous other factors related to the market in general or to the implementation of any specific trading program which cannot be fully accounted for in the preparation of hypothetical performance results and all of which can adversely affect actual trading results. ****
  8. **REGISTERED USERS.**

Certain services, such as advanced screeners or portfolios, are available only to registered users of the Barchart.com website and require you to sign in with a user name and password to use them. If you register as a user (a “Subscriber”) of any of the features of Barchart.com, during the registration process you may be prompted to click an “Register Now,” “Submit” or similar button; your clicking on such button will further confirm your agreement to be legally bound by these Terms and Conditions.

In consideration of your use of the Barchart.com website, you represent that you are of legal age to form a binding contract and are not a person barred from receiving Barchart.com Services under the laws of the United States or other applicable jurisdiction. You also agree to: (a) provide true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself as prompted by the Barchart.com's registration form (the "Registration Data") and (b) maintain and promptly update the Registration Data to keep it true, accurate, current and complete. If you provide any information that is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, or Barchart.com has reasonable grounds to suspect that such information is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, Barchart.com has the right to suspend or terminate your account and refuse any and all current or future use of the Barchart.com Services (or any portion thereof).   

  9. **USER CONTENT**

Registered users may have the ability to upload images, including photos representing them on Barchart.com. You are solely responsible for the photos you may upload on or through Barchart.com. By uploading a photo you certify that you have the right to distribute it. 

You may not post, or share content on Barchart.com that you did not create or that you do not have permission to post. You understand and agree that the Barchart.com editorial team may, but is not obligated to, review the Site and may delete or remove (without notice) any content in its sole discretion, for any reason. You are solely responsible at your sole cost and expense for creating backup copies and replacing any content you post on Barchart.   
Damaging, threatening, fraudulent, or pornographic user content, including pictures, is strictly prohibited on Barchart.com. Barchart reserves the right to remove any such content at its discretion. 

  10. **ACCESS AND SECURITY**

You accept responsibility for the confidentiality and use of any user name and email address that you may register for your access to and use of the Services. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of the password and account and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your password or account. You agree to (a) immediately notify Barchart.com of any unauthorized use of your password or account or any other breach of security, and (b) ensure that you exit from your account at the end of each session. Barchart.com cannot and will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from your failure to comply. 

  11. **FEEDBACK TO BARCHART.COM  
**  
By submitting ideas, suggestions, documents, and/or proposals to Barchart.com through its contact or feedback webpages, you acknowledge and agree that: (a) your Contributions do not contain confidential or proprietary information; (b) Barchart.com is not under any obligation of confidentiality, express or implied, with respect to the Contributions; (c) Barchart.com shall be entitled to use or disclose (or choose not to use or disclose) such Contributions for any purpose, in any way, in any media worldwide; (d) Barchart.com may have something similar to the Contributions already under consideration or in development; (e) your Contributions automatically become the property of Barchart.com without any obligation of Barchart.com to you; and (f) you are not entitled to any compensation or reimbursement of any kind from Barchart.com under any circumstances.
  12. **INDEMNITY**

You agree to indemnify and hold Barchart.com and its subsidiaries, affiliates, officers, agents, employees, partners and licensors harmless from any claim or demand, including reasonable attorneys' fees, made by any third party due to or arising out of Content you submit, post, transmit, modify or otherwise make available through the Barchart.com Services, your use of the Barchart.com Services, your connection to the Barchart.com Services, your violation of the Terms of Use, or your violation of any rights of another.

  13. **TERMINATION**

You may terminate your Barchart.com account, any associated email address and access to the Barchart.com Services by submitting such termination request to Barchart.com. 

You agree that Barchart.com may, without prior notice, immediately terminate, limit your access to or suspend your Barchart.com account, any associated email address, and access to the Barchart.com Services. Cause for such termination, limitation of access or suspension shall include, but not be limited to, (a) breaches or violations of the Terms of Use or other incorporated agreements or guidelines, (b)requests by law enforcement or other government agencies, (c) discontinuance or material modification to the Barchart.com Services (or any part thereof), (d) unexpected technical or security issues or problems, (e) extended periods of inactivity, (f) and/or engagement by you in fraudulent or illegal activities. Further, you agree that all terminations, limitations of access and suspensions for cause shall be made in Barchart.com's sole discretion and that Barchart.com shall not be liable to you or any third party for any termination of your account, any associated email address, or access to the Barchart.com Services.

## Privacy Policy

Effective November 23, 2015

This statement discloses the privacy, security, and information management guidelines that serve as the basis for our user relationships with respect to users of all websites that display a link to this Privacy Policy and that are published by Barchart.com (collectively, “Barchart.com”). Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy.

Because Internet technologies are rapidly evolving and underlying business models are evolving with them, this statement is subject to change. Any such changes will be posted on this page.

**What information does Barchart.com collect?**

As described below herein, Barchart.com collects registration information, other information that you choose share or post, and information relating to your online interactions on Barchart.com sites. Barchart.com uses a registration system for My Barchart customers. Users provide information including but not limited to name, email address, street address, and other demographic information. Barchart.com collects information about your transactions with us and with some of our business partners, including information about your use of financial products and services that we offer. 

Barchart.com also collects personal information when you use Barchart.com's additional products or services, when you visit Barchart.com pages or the pages of certain Barchart.com partners, and when you sign up for promotions or sweepstakes. Barchart.com may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies. The information collected by Barchart about you may include: 

  * Registration information filled out during the registration process or acquired via the Facebook Graph API including but not limited to name, picture, email address, street address, gender, birthdate, work history, education history, and other demographic information.
  * Information you choose to share including but not limited to comments on users' feeds (including your own) and on news stories, your stock picks, your votes and any other editorial information you publish on the Barchart Network feed pages.
  * Information received from friends and others, including but not limited to when they upload your contact information.
  * IP addresses. (Your IP address indicates the location of your computer on the internet. It is not necessarily a unique personal identifier.)

For certain advanced subscription features, Barchart.com automatically receives and records information from your computer and browser, including cookie and/or beacon information, software and hardware attributes, and the page you request. 

**Can you “opt out” of providing personally identifying information or receiving marketing messages?**

You may “opt out” altogether from providing personally identifying information to us by not registering with Barchart.com and thereby not providing personal information, or by not visiting the Barchart.com sites. You can delete your Barchart.com account by sending us a message with your user name and password. If you choose not to register or provide mandatory information in the registration form, Barchart.com will not be fully accessible to you. You can edit your Account Information, including your newsletter preferences, at any time. Commercial email communications from Barchart.com comes with an unsubscribe link at the bottom for you to opt-out of future such marketing communications. 

**How does Barchart.com protect its content and user information?**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online, including encryption security for credit card submissions. Such commercially reasonable precautions, however, do not absolutely guarantee the absolute protection of your personally identifying information. You must understand that there will always be some risk that any personally identifying information that you provide to us may be released without our permission or knowledge.

**What does Barchart.com do with the information it gathers and/or tracks?**

Barchart.com uses information for the following general purposes: to fulfill your requests for products and services, to customize the advertising and content you see, to improve our services, to contact you, to conduct research, and to provide trend reporting for internal and external clients.

To make it easier for your friends to find you, we allow anyone with your name to find you through the Barchart search bar at the top of most users' feeds, as well as other tools we provide, such as contact importers - even if you have not shared your contact information with them on Barchart. You can choose to opt out of this feature in your account section. If you choose to opt out you will not be queryable in the search bar using your first or last name. Public items such as comments on news stories will however remain visible by all users registered on Barchart.

Barchart.com may also display targeted advertisements based on personal information. Advertisers (including ad serving companies) may assume that people who interact with, view, or click targeted ads meet the targeting criteria—for example, people trading agricultural products from a particular geographic area. 

We may send you certain communications relating to the Barchart.com service, such as service announcements, administrative messages and the Barchart.com Newsletter, that are considered part of your Barchart.com account. 

**With whom does Barchart.com share the information it gathers and/or tracks?**

Barchart.com shares the information it gathers, in aggregate form, with advertisers and other partners. It also provides information to trusted partners who work with or on behalf of Barchart.com. These companies may use your personal information for, among other things, to help Barchart.com communicate with you about offers from Barchart.com and our marketing partners. We also may share information about you, including personally identifying information, if sought by legal process or requested by law enforcement, or in order to protect the rights and property of Barchart.com or the safety of our users or the public, or to protect against unauthorized use of our site.

If Barchart.com is acquired by another company or otherwise merged into another company, we will transfer collected registrant and user information subject to this policy to a successor. In the event that information will be subject to a materially different privacy policy, Barchart.com or its successor will provide notice.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the "Shine The Light" law, permits our customers who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to:

Barchart.com  
209 W. Jackson  
Chicago, IL 60606

**Revisions**

From time to time Barchart.com may review and update this policy.
